royalnavy.mod.uk 2019-04-26

# Privacy | Royal Navy

This privacy statement only covers the Royal Navy website at www.royalnavy.mod.uk 

###### Date last modified: 26/06/2018

#### Who we are:

The Royal Navy website is provided by the Ministry of Defence with the agreement of the Government Digital Service (GDS) which is part of the Cabinet Office. The job of the Government Digital Service is the digital transformation of government.

GDS are a centre of excellence in digital, technology and data, collaborating with departments to help them with their own transformation. We work with them to build platforms, standards and digital services, and the Royal Navy website is approved through the Government Digital Service. The data controller for GDS is the Cabinet Office – a data controller determines the purposes and means of processing personal data. For more information see the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) Data Protection Public Register. The Cabinet Office registration number is: Z7414053.

Full details of the Ministry of Defence Privacy notice can be found here: <https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice>

It includes:

  1. [Purpose of this document](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#purpose-of-this-document)
  2. [Data protection principles](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#data-protection-principles)
  3. [The identity and contact details of MOD Data Controller and Data Protection Officer](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#the-identity-and-contact-details-of-mod-data-controller-and-data-protection-officer)
  4. [The kind of information we hold about you](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#the-kind-of-information-we-hold-about-you)
  5. [How we collect or process your data](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#how-we-collect-or-process-your-data)
  6. Our legal basis for processing your personal data
  7. [Why are we collecting or processing your data](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#why-are-we-collecting-or-processing-your-data)
  8. [If you fail to provide personal information](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#if-you-fail-to-provide-personal-information)
  9. [Change of purpose](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#change-of-purpose)
  10. [How we use particularly sensitive personal information](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#how-we-use-particularly-sensitive-personal-information)
  11. [Do we need your consent?](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#do-we-need-your-consent)
  12. [Information about criminal convictions](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#information-about-criminal-convictions)
  13. [Automated decision making](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#automated-decision-making)
  14. [How we store personal data](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#how-we-store-personal-data)
  15. [Sharing your personal data](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#sharing-your-personal-data)
  16. [For how long we will keep the personal data, or criteria used to determine the retention period](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#for-how-long-we-will-keep-the-personal-data-or-criteria-used-to-determine-the-retention-period)
  17. [Duty to inform](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#duty-to-inform)
  18. [Your rights](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#your-rights)
  19. [How to complain](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#how-to-complain)
  20. [Changes to this privacy notice](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ministry-of-defence-privacy-notice/mod-privacy-notice#changes-to-this-privacy-notice)

#### What we do with it:

We will not:

  * sell or rent your data to third parties
  * share your data with third parties for marketing purposes
  * We will share your data if we are required to do so by law – for example, by court order, or to prevent fraud or other crime

#### **Children’s privacy protection:**

We understand the importance of protecting children's privacy online. Our services are not designed for, or intentionally targeted at, children 13 years of age or younger. It is not our policy to intentionally collect or maintain data about anyone under the age of 13.

#### **Where it might go:**

We will in some circumstances have to share your data with third parties, including third-party service providers and other Civil Service bodies. We require third parties to respect the security of your data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We will in some circumstances transfer your personal information outside the EU. If we do, you can expect a similar degree of protection in respect of your personal information.

####  How we protect your data and keep it secure:

Our IT infrastructure and technology has been validated from inception to delivery with supporting contracts to ensure compliance with all data sharing activities.

We are committed to doing all that we can to keep your data secure. To prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place technical and organisational procedures to secure the data we collect about you – for example, we protect your data using varying levels of encryption. We also make sure that any third parties that we deal with have an obligation to keep all personal data they process on our behalf secure.

####  What are your rights

You have the right to:

  * request information about how your personal data are processed and to request a copy of that personal data
  * request that any inaccuracies in your personal data are rectified without delay
  * request that any incomplete personal data are completed, including by means of a supplementary statement request that your personal data are erased if there is no longer a justification for them to be processed request that the processing of your personal data is restricted in certain circumstances – for example, where accuracy is contested

If your personal data is processed on the basis of consent, you have the right to:

  * withdraw consent to the processing of your personal data at any time
  * request a copy of any personal data you have provided, and for this to be provided in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format

#### **Changes to this notice**

We may modify or amend this privacy notice at our discretion at any time. When we make changes to this notice, we will amend the last modified data at the top of this page. Any modification or amendment to this privacy notice will be applied to you and your data as of that revision date. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy notice to be informed about how we are protecting your data.

####  How to contact us:

If you have an issue with the Royal Navy website, please contact us through the contact us form here: <https://www.royalnavy.mod.uk/contact-us> The Ministry of Defence is the data controller. The contact details are:

**MOD Data Protection Officer**  
Ground floor, zone D   
Main Building  
Whitehall   
London   
SW1A 2HB

Email: [cio-dpa@mod.gov.uk](mailto:cio-dpa@mod.gov.uk)

You may also make a complaint to the Information Commissioner, who is an independent regulator. The Information Commissioner can be contacted at: [casework@ico.org.uk](mailto:casework@ico.org.uk) or on 0303 123 1113.

Or by post at:

Information Commissioner's Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire SK9 5AF
